<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grid computing on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/grid-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grid computing on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 08:38:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/grid-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>April Is For AOL</title>
      <link>/2008/04/april-is-for-aol.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 08:38:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/04/april-is-for-aol.html</guid>
      <description>Last night was the always fun Los Angeles web application developer Meetup, this time at AOL in Beverly Hills. After navigating a veritable maze of cubes, we found ourselves in a fairly large screening room chock full of AV equipment, accompanied by a large pile of pizza boxes. A few moments later, the throng of LA-based developers shuffled in, ready for the latest and greatest. The prerequisites fulfilled, we got down to some serious techno-babble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everybody Into The Pool</title>
      <link>/2008/02/everybody-into-pool.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 11:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/everybody-into-pool.html</guid>
      <description>A few weeks back, I indulged my current obsession with grid computing, and Amazon&amp;rsquo;s EC2 and S3 services in particular, with a lengthy post. I mentioned how friend Ari Lerner and I had built a really neat solution, and were going to put all of our processing farm goodness into a nice neat gemified package. Well, mostly thanks to Ari, we now have a new Ruby gem called ProcessorPool that uses EC2 and S3 to do all the hard work for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Grid With EC2</title>
      <link>/2008/01/on-grid-with-ec2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 10:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/on-grid-with-ec2.html</guid>
      <description>Lately, I have had a chance to get seriously into Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) service. I doubt any reader of this blog is unfamiliar with the existence of EC2, but many of you have probably not even gotten to the tire kicking stage, like I had been until recently.
Even after attending several sessions about Amazon&amp;rsquo;s EC2 at RailsConf 2007, I still had only a very general idea about the service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
