<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby.net on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/ruby.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruby.net on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 06:05:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ruby.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ruby.NET, We Hardly Knew Ye</title>
      <link>/2008/02/rubynet-we-hardly-knew-ye.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 06:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/rubynet-we-hardly-knew-ye.html</guid>
      <description>It comes as not entirely surprising that the Wayne Kelly of the Ruby.NET project from down under has finally given up the ship. Microsoft had already grabbed the spotlight with IronRuby and the DLR. Despite some early gains, it seemed that development momentum had peaked, until Ruby.NET finally made its way up onto Google Code and a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; open source project.
How, how will John Lam and team proceed without Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2007 =&gt; Ruby VM Smackdown</title>
      <link>/2007/09/rubyconf-2007-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 09:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/09/rubyconf-2007-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</guid>
      <description>I just registered for RubyConf 2007, which will be held Nov. 2-4 in Charlotte, NC. If you want a more intimate, more hard-core Rubyist experience, than what RailsConf is turning into, RubyConf looks to be it.
There not being that many tickets available, you better register right now if you want to go. I registered without even looking at the agenda first&amp;hellip; just filled out the registration form, and hoped it&amp;rsquo;s was not too late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IronRuby Lives!</title>
      <link>/2007/07/ironruby-lives.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 08:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/07/ironruby-lives.html</guid>
      <description>John Lam and company have finally gotten something together to release to the world at large for their IronRuby project. I have not had a chance to play with it yet, but as a hard-core Rubyist I will, of course, have to do so.
A few interesting observations from how they have chosen to go about developing this project. One is that they are distributing the source code, albeit as part of the Microsoft Permissive License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Is More Of A Free Love Kind Of Language</title>
      <link>/2007/07/ruby-is-more-of-free-love-kind-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 08:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/07/ruby-is-more-of-free-love-kind-of.html</guid>
      <description>I have been really, really busy lately, which is why I have not had a chance to post anything. I finally caught up on some reading and listening, and John Lam, father of the IronRuby project at Microsoft, has a fun interview on the DotNetRocks podcast. Irrespective of how I may currently feel about the direction over at Microsoft or rock, it is an interesting interview.
My favorite line has to be where John is describing the cultural differences between the users of Python vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby/Microsoft?</title>
      <link>/2007/05/rubymicrosoft.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/rubymicrosoft.html</guid>
      <description>Martin Fowler just posted on his bliki a little piece entitled RubyMicrosoft. As I read it, I felt a strange chill run down my spine. Perhaps a few words of explanation are needed&amp;hellip;
At RailsConf recently I stood at the Thoughtworks booth for a moment chatting up Fowler, and embarrassing myself by asking for a photo with him (he doesn&amp;rsquo;t pose for photos with people). Luckily, I was rescued by the arrival of Oli Bini, and an ensuing short discussion about JRuby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silverlight and Ruby?</title>
      <link>/2007/04/silverlight-and-ruby.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 16:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/04/silverlight-and-ruby.html</guid>
      <description>Today, Microsoft announced their Silverlight technology platform. I will not bore you, kind reader, with yet another recap of what has already been written by so many others already.
However, there are a couple of curious details that have piqued my interest. John Lam, of RubyCLR fame, made an interesting comment on his blog earlier today about Silverlight:
 This was a major reason why I moved my family to the other side of the continent&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ruby.NET Interview From Down Under</title>
      <link>/2007/03/rubynet-interview-from-down-under.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2007 15:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/rubynet-interview-from-down-under.html</guid>
      <description>An interview with Dr. Wayne Kelly has been put up on Channel 9, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s video interview site. Dr. Kelly is head of the Ruby.NET compiler project at the Queensland University of Technology in Australia. As always, I am eager to see progress on the .NET side of the Ruby language wars. I drank my coffee, and put on my phones for the 15 minute interview.
After watching the video, I must say I am a little underwhelmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JRuby Has Won The Rails Race vs. .NET</title>
      <link>/2007/03/jruby-has-won-rails-race-vs-net.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 21:34:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/jruby-has-won-rails-race-vs-net.html</guid>
      <description>So now it is official. The latest build from the JRuby team is now running Ruby on Rails in the JRuby runtime. Great work from that team! The Sunsters up top must be gloating right now.
And Microsoft is still MIA. Despite some hopeful signs of life, the silence is deafening from Ray Ozzie and the .NET camp (is that a band?). MS had better have some damn strong announcement at MIX vis-à-vis Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even eWeek Is Falling For Ruby</title>
      <link>/2007/02/even-eweek-is-falling-for-ruby.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 14:47:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/even-eweek-is-falling-for-ruby.html</guid>
      <description>Even that stanch old &amp;ldquo;enterprisey&amp;rdquo; publication eWeek has been giving some love to Ruby and Ruby on Rails. Today&amp;rsquo;s most recent article is entitled &amp;ldquo;Ruby, Ruby, When Will You Be Mine?&amp;quot;. Was this supposed to run on Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day? I&amp;rsquo;m definitely feeling the love in the title.
Anyhow, the author is all over the JRuby project. Messrs. Nutter et. al. have been building up the energy at the same time as the code base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby.NET and REXML: Not Yet</title>
      <link>/2007/02/rubynet-and-rexml-not-yet.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 11:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/rubynet-and-rexml-not-yet.html</guid>
      <description>I finally had a chance to play around with the latest download of the Gardens Point Ruby.NET compiler. At first, I was excited, as my little DSL test application was able to run perfectly. Blocks, instance_eval, singleton classes all worked fine for me. Very cool!
Then I decided to experiment with the REXML ruby parser. I did so despite the fact that the compiler authors have stated in their project goals that &amp;ldquo;We do not however plan to implement the other Ruby libraries that commonly ship with the Ruby distribution, such as CGI and DBM (except for those implemented 100% in Ruby)&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby.NET Lives!</title>
      <link>/2007/02/rubynet-lives.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2007 10:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/rubynet-lives.html</guid>
      <description>It has been radio silence for quite a while from the Ruby.NET project. Well, the eagle had landed. There is a new beta release.
Here is what they have to say for themselves:
 We are pleased to announce the release of a new Beta (version 0.6) of the Gardens Point Ruby.NET compiler. Implementation is not yet complete but we have now implemented the vast majority of Ruby&amp;rsquo;s builtin classes and modules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
