<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>silverlight on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/silverlight/</link>
    <description>Recent content in silverlight on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 13:38:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/silverlight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2007 - Day 2 - &#34;The Ruby VM Smackdown Begins&#34;</title>
      <link>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-2-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 13:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-2-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</guid>
      <description>As the sun rose over the hills of North Carolina, the quiet betrayed a seething fire blazing in the hearts of three development teams. &amp;ldquo;Three teams enter, one team leaves!&amp;rdquo; Yes, I am talking about the main event, people, the one, the only, Ruby VM Smackdown! The room was jam packed, the anticipation was high.
As good fortune would have it, I was sitting right next to the head of the team who was my personal favorite to win the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Developer Fun In Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/2007/10/more-developer-fun-in-los-angeles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 08:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/10/more-developer-fun-in-los-angeles.html</guid>
      <description>Last night was the always entertaining Los Angeles Application Developer Meetup. L.A. is not known for the same massive quantity of developers as the bay area, for example, but having joined forces with the LA Ruby on Rails Meetup crew some time back, the monthly event is still growing.
This month&amp;rsquo;s was held at the impressive new digs of YellowPages.com, who have been busy building out a huge Ruby on Rails based local search replacement for their venerable 100K+ lines of Java code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silverlight and Ruby?</title>
      <link>/2007/04/silverlight-and-ruby.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 16:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/04/silverlight-and-ruby.html</guid>
      <description>Today, Microsoft announced their Silverlight technology platform. I will not bore you, kind reader, with yet another recap of what has already been written by so many others already.
However, there are a couple of curious details that have piqued my interest. John Lam, of RubyCLR fame, made an interesting comment on his blog earlier today about Silverlight:
 This was a major reason why I moved my family to the other side of the continent&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
