<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cloud computing on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/cloud-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cloud computing on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 09:28:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cloud-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Heroku Has Launched</title>
      <link>/2009/04/heroku-has-launched.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 09:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/heroku-has-launched.html</guid>
      <description>Well, just a very short time after I started using Heroku, they went commercial. Yes, after their very successful beta period, where apparently 24,999 web sites other than mine were already hosting, Heroku is now offering a paid version of their service. I had a sneak peak at the pricing a few days ahead of time, but I was not able to talk. And despite my intentions of blogging this right away, the other demands on my time have kept me occupied till just now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroku, Why Haven&#39;t I Been Using You Till Now?</title>
      <link>/2009/04/heroku-why-havent-i-been-using-you-till.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 11:23:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/heroku-why-havent-i-been-using-you-till.html</guid>
      <description>Last night, I finally got around to deploying something on Heroku, an interesting service founded by my formerly LA-based Ruby programming chums Adam Wiggins, James Lindenbaum, and Orion Henry. I had played with their previous incarnation of the service, now known as &amp;ldquo;Heroku Garden&amp;rdquo; but only recently have I gotten to know a little bit more about the incredible offering they have evolved into.
Basically, the Heroku crew have addressed the question &amp;ldquo;how can I deploy my Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, or other Rack-based web application into a dynamic cloud of servers with ridiculous ease?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
