<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>softer side of development on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/softer-side-of-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in softer side of development on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 14:29:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/softer-side-of-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modern Web Design</title>
      <link>/2008/05/modern-web-design.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 14:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/05/modern-web-design.html</guid>
      <description>This one pie chart says it all&amp;hellip;
From ChangeTheThought.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goldilocks and The Three Icons</title>
      <link>/2008/04/goldilocks-and-three-icons.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 18:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/04/goldilocks-and-three-icons.html</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time, there were three icons. A Poppa Application icon, a Momma Folder icon and a Baby Document icon. Life was good, and people were easily able to tell the difference between them, although very few visitors were known to go to that part of the forest.
But then along came the Trashcan icon&amp;hellip; and the dark times began. If you dragged a folder to the trash it went away back into the void.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eyes Have It</title>
      <link>/2007/11/eyes-have-it.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 08:06:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/11/eyes-have-it.html</guid>
      <description>Software usability has really benefited from the latest and greatest digital technology for eye tracking. If you are not familiar with eye tracking, it is exactly what it sounds like: a camera watching where the user&amp;rsquo;s eyes are focused, and matching that to the screen to identify what the user is REALLY looking at, for how long, and in what order.
Here is a really great summary called &amp;ldquo;Scientific Web Design: 23 Actionable Lessons from Eye-Tracking Studies&amp;rdquo; that collects information from several different studies, and packages it up into something pretty, dare I say it, usable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The R/evolution Will Not Be On Television</title>
      <link>/2007/10/revolution-will-not-be-on-television.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 08:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/10/revolution-will-not-be-on-television.html</guid>
      <description>The medium of video is better than ever, thanks to YouTube. Video content is a lot improved by splitting video into smaller pieces, making the videos searchable, and most importantly, allowing for self-publishing. Helping for niche content authors to get their message out, has as a natural effect, a large proportion of idiocratic nonsense, but there are gems buried in the muck.
Nothing to me is more emblematic of this, than the brilliant videos put together by Michael Wesch of Kansas State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Proper Use Of Color</title>
      <link>/2007/10/proper-use-of-color.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 11:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/10/proper-use-of-color.html</guid>
      <description>Really cool article here from of all places NASA (go figure) courtesy of the Signal Vs. Noise blog. Entitled &amp;ldquo;DESIGNING A COLOR GRAPHICS PAGE&amp;rdquo;, it really breaks down a process of utilizing color to maximize user understanding of information.
Color for its own sake is better kept to the domain of art. Functional design, like that of software user interfaces, need to be much better thought out, reaching for both utility and aesthetic qualities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualize This</title>
      <link>/2007/08/visualize-this.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 18:11:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/08/visualize-this.html</guid>
      <description>Did you ever want to present information in a visual format, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know which one was most appropriate? Don&amp;rsquo;t know a Petri net from a concept fan? Or perhaps you just need even more visual stimulus from your information?
Well, welcome to a feast of visualization splendor. Just have a glance at the Periodic Table of Visualization Methods&amp;hellip; your eyes will never go hungry again.
Thanks to Visual Literacy for creating this great info, and to Jeff Atwood of Coding Horror for blogging about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Rangers Should Test First</title>
      <link>/2007/06/power-rangers-should-test-first.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 15:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/06/power-rangers-should-test-first.html</guid>
      <description>Last night, I got home a bit late. My 8 year old son was still up, watching the Power Rangers. &amp;ldquo;Sit down and watch with me, Dad,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m surprised you still like the Power Rangers,&amp;rdquo; I said, as I sat beside him on the sofa. &amp;ldquo;I mostly just like the vehicles,&amp;rdquo; he told me.
The Power Rangers were in trouble in this episode. The bad guys had taken remote control of the Rangers&#39; giant robots, and the Power Rangers were helpless without their usual firepower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Would Rather Be A Jazz Programmer</title>
      <link>/2007/05/i-would-rather-be-jazz-programmer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 12:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/i-would-rather-be-jazz-programmer.html</guid>
      <description>I have reading a bit lately about &amp;ldquo;rockstar&amp;rdquo; programmers. Recruiter ads are proclaiming &amp;ldquo;Rockstar programmer needed&amp;rdquo;. Various websites named rockstaror alternately rockstars are springing up everywhere.
I would rather be a &amp;ldquo;jazz musician&amp;rdquo; programmer, myself. Nothing against rock, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. Glam, punk, metal, I can go there. I frequently do. It&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;star&amp;rdquo; part, that has been starting to bother me.
Here are some differences, as I see them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing The Code</title>
      <link>/2007/04/growing-code.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2007 13:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/04/growing-code.html</guid>
      <description>Kevin Barnes over at Code Craft has a cool posting comparing software development to gardening. I agree with him that it is a fantastic analogy!
It really rings true to me in a couple of fun ways:
  Gardening cannot be done once and for ever. It takes constant work to keep it both healthy and tidy.
  There is a big difference in both purpose and aesthetics within different gardens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommuting as energy saver</title>
      <link>/2007/02/telecommuting-as-energy-saver.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 17:33:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/telecommuting-as-energy-saver.html</guid>
      <description>The Christian Science Monitor has an opinion piece called Telecommuting as energy saver which is nicely done.
Here are a few juicy excerpts:
 This new work freedom, properly handled, has the power to transform business, government, and home life. Telecommuters – those who work at home or on the road with no office at all – now number between 28 million and 32 million, according to some estimates&amp;hellip;
Cutting out that round-trip commute to the office – which averages about 23 miles – can save nearly $1,000 a year in gasoline and avoid putting more than 6,000 pounds of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People are communicating beings</title>
      <link>/2007/01/people-are-communicating-beings.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2007 10:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/01/people-are-communicating-beings.html</guid>
      <description>I ran into this older article from Alistair Cockburn the other day called Characterizing people as non-linear, first-order components in software development.
What Dr. Cockburn is talking about, is that very agile of ideas that people are the central focus for any software development effort. Developing software is not just a sausage factory of requirement documents, source code documents, and unit test plan documents. The people are what is important, not the documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beating a Dead Horse</title>
      <link>/2007/01/beating-dead-horse.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 16:16:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/01/beating-dead-horse.html</guid>
      <description>Last week, there was a very funny post from the extreme programming mailing list, published here.
This is quite emblematic of what dead programmers see every day, as we are often ordered to ride dead horses&amp;hellip;
We need to add a couple to the list:
- Offshore the dead horse so we can ride it 24 hours a day
- Mandate all riding be done on site, so we can keep an eye on our dead horse</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Folly of Accountabalism</title>
      <link>/2007/01/folly-of-accountabalism.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 14:41:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/01/folly-of-accountabalism.html</guid>
      <description>The Harvard Business Review has published their list of 20 breakthrough ideas for 2007. There are several ideas on this list with particular appeal to me. One that stands out is David Weinberger&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Folly of Accountabalism&amp;rdquo; which insists that &amp;ldquo;Accountability has gone horribly wrong. It has become &amp;lsquo;accountabalism,&amp;rsquo; the practice of eating sacrificial victims in an attempt to magically ward off evil.&amp;rdquo;
Dr. Weinberger is referring to the emphasis on corporate management and compliance that has come to dominate modern American business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Anti-Team</title>
      <link>/2007/01/anti-team.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2007 16:43:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/01/anti-team.html</guid>
      <description>Jeremy Miller and Ayende have each captured some hysterical and yet poignant slices of life from the depths of the seventh pit of hell&amp;hellip;or your typical IT project team, as most of us more commonly know it.
If you are guilty, you know who you are. If you are innocent, then you haven&amp;rsquo;t been working very long in this game&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewrite Of No Return</title>
      <link>/2007/01/rewrite-of-no-return.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2007 10:02:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/01/rewrite-of-no-return.html</guid>
      <description>I am really into Kevin Barnes&#39; article &amp;ldquo;To Rewrite Or Not To Rewrite&amp;rdquo;. He is on the right track about the challenges and tactics for a rewrite of any complexity. Chad Fowler is also exploring the big rewrite, and has fun things to say in a whole series of postings.
Rewriting a system too soon can be a waste of resources. One of the points of SOA is to allows services to be rewritten as needed, not just because a cool new technology can come out, but because there is value to be gained from doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistance To Change</title>
      <link>/2006/12/resistance-to-change.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2006 11:29:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2006/12/resistance-to-change.html</guid>
      <description>Obie Fernandez comments on Seth Godin&amp;rsquo;s observation that he would be a lousy pilot. Maybe this explains why I do not have a pilot&amp;rsquo;s license&amp;hellip;
Obie notes that &amp;ldquo;innovators catch the most grief from management&amp;rdquo;. But why would this be the case, when management is so eager to capitalize on said innovations? Perhaps a look at anthropology can help. A few years ago I watched a fantastic program on the Discovery Channel called &amp;ldquo;Walking With Cavemen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Zombies Will Crush You</title>
      <link>/2006/10/programming-zombies-will-crush-you.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2006 14:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2006/10/programming-zombies-will-crush-you.html</guid>
      <description>This post on the &amp;ldquo;Creating Passionate Users&amp;rdquo; blog really sums up what makes a Dead Programmer, well&amp;hellip;.dead!
http://headrush.typepad.com/creating_passionate_users/2006/10/knocking_the_ex.html
A colleague of mine once quipped, &amp;ldquo;Why is it that at some point in most people&amp;rsquo;s career, they suddenly decide that they now know everything and don&amp;rsquo;t have anything else to learn?&amp;rdquo;. That is around the point that they are past the point of no return converging on the &amp;ldquo;micro-manage every detail&amp;rdquo; side of the &amp;ldquo;Zombie Function&amp;rdquo; graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Skilled For Programming?</title>
      <link>/2006/10/too-skilled-for-programming.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2006 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2006/10/too-skilled-for-programming.html</guid>
      <description>This classic bit of wisdom from David Dossot explains many things about management philosophy that frequently make little sense to developers. If you ever wondered how some people ended up in management, the answer is here:
http://perso.wanadoo.fr/lothar/datastore/TooSkilledForProgramming.pdf
In a world where taller people tend to more successful, I guess it makes sense. But logic has nothing to do with it! And things that lack logic offend the sensibilities of any self-respecting Dead Programmer&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
