<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>postgres on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/postgres/</link>
    <description>Recent content in postgres on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2009 11:19:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/postgres/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL on Ubuntu on EC2: Backing It All Up</title>
      <link>/2009/10/postgresql-on-ubuntu-on-ec2-backing-it.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2009 11:19:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/10/postgresql-on-ubuntu-on-ec2-backing-it.html</guid>
      <description>This post continues what I started with &amp;ldquo;PostgreSQL on Ubuntu on EC2: The Installation Guide&amp;rdquo;. Once you have your PostgreSQL database server instance running, you will need to backup two different things: your database data, and the instance itself. The database data will be backed up using Elastic Block Storage (EBS) snapshots. Once we have the instance running the backups correctly, we will then create an Amazon Machine Image (AMI) that will allow you to launch a new instance to replace the database server in case it goes down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL on Ubuntu on EC2: The Installation Guide</title>
      <link>/2009/08/postgresql-on-ubuntu-on-ec2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 01:27:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/08/postgresql-on-ubuntu-on-ec2.html</guid>
      <description>For some time, I have had clients hosting a couple different applications on Amazon EC2 using Ubuntu. One of these apps uses PostgreSQL, and has been running without event for quite a while. Yesterday, I got to catch up for lost time, by spending the entire day wrestling with data recovery issues related to a failed apt-get upgrade on an important database server. Luckily, the awesome Eric Hammond was around on IRC, came to my rescue, and coached my thru my self-inflicted pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search Of Search</title>
      <link>/2008/05/in-search-of-search.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 15:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/05/in-search-of-search.html</guid>
      <description>My client was having troubles. The site was crashing, seemingly at random. QA was baffled, management concerned. After hunting thru logs, the culprit was found: the ferret search service.
Despite having configured acts_as_ferret to use the DRb server option, the &amp;ldquo;whole thing&amp;rdquo; would fall apart on a regular basis whenever the ferret daemon would crash&amp;hellip; which was pretty often. The ruby on rails plugin acts_as_ferret would revert to a local mode of operation, which would only make matters worse when competing mongrels would corrupt the index files on disk.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
