<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rubyconf2008 on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/rubyconf2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rubyconf2008 on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 09:07:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/rubyconf2008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2008 - Day 1 - Testing Heresies - Francis Hwang</title>
      <link>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-day-1-testing-heresies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 09:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-day-1-testing-heresies.html</guid>
      <description>The sessions for RubyConf 2008 day one were nearly over, when I attending this highly entertaining and informative one. I had missed the chance to see a previous presentation by Francis Hwang, and being as test-obsessed as I am, I was not going to make the same mistake twice.
Many people are confused over mocks, stubs, and other fakes. Here are the real definitions.
Gerard Meszaros - Test Doubles
- dummies - passed around but never used</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2008 - Day 1 - rush, a shell that will yield to you - Nicholas Schlueter</title>
      <link>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-rush-shell-that-will.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 06:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-rush-shell-that-will.html</guid>
      <description>I had previously blogged a bit about Rush, the Ruby shell. Well, now Rush must now be its own force to be reckoned with, because this presentation was NOT by Adam Wiggins, the creator of Rush, but was instead by Nicholas Schlueter, the creator of RushMate. If you&amp;rsquo;ve not heard of it, RushMate allows you to use Rush from within TextMate, which translates to being able to write custom commands much more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2008 - Rubinius - Evan Phoenix</title>
      <link>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-rubinius-evan-phoenix.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 21:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-rubinius-evan-phoenix.html</guid>
      <description>The Ruby VM wonkiness continued at RubyConf 2008 - Day 1. Next up we heard the &amp;ldquo;State of Rubinius&amp;rdquo; address on the status of the anointed heir to the Ruby federation. Evan Phoenix is a fun guy, and it proved to be a both informative and enjoyable session.
Evan says Rubinius is &amp;ldquo;meta-circular-ish&amp;rdquo;, and slow, but getting faster. They have a new VM that is written in C++, which is a sharp tool, and as such, it is possible to poke your eye out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2008 - Future of RubyVM - Koichi Sasada</title>
      <link>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-future-of-rubyvm-koichi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 10:13:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-future-of-rubyvm-koichi.html</guid>
      <description>The first session I attended at RubyConf 2008 was called &amp;ldquo;Future of RubyVM&amp;rdquo;, and it began my ascent into &amp;ldquo;VM Wonkiness&amp;rdquo; as I started to call it. Koichi-san is responsible for leading the team of Ruby 1.9 implementers, and is the authoritative source of info on its status. I was hoping to learn a few things, as well as to run into new acquaintance Nobuyoshi Nakada, one of the core team members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2008 - Day 1</title>
      <link>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 09:58:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-day-1.html</guid>
      <description>The crowd of over 400 was happily awaiting the kickoff in Orlando of RubyConf 2008. After brief introductions from Rich Kilmer and David Black, Matz took the stage for his opening keynote.
Opening Keynote - Matz
Reasons Behind Ruby
8 years ago was the 1st International Ruby Conference, and there were only 33 people there. Obviously since then, the community has grown. Matz said he was not going to talk about technical stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going To RubyConf 2008</title>
      <link>/2008/09/going-to-rubyconf-2008.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 16:54:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/09/going-to-rubyconf-2008.html</guid>
      <description>Yes, it has been quite a while since I last posted. I have been busy with several interesting code things I will be talking about soon, along with my family&amp;rsquo;s annual trip to Spain (lots of good times, but no posting about that).
Busy, yes. but not TOO busy to make my plans to go to RubyConf 2008. November in Florida, I can just imagine it now&amp;hellip; hard core Ruby coding, jam sessions in the hotel, and maybe even some post-election riots.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
