<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>los angeles on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/los-angeles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in los angeles on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:08:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/los-angeles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Should We Call It Mails, or Rurb? Yahuda Katz Clears Things Up At The LA Ruby Meetup</title>
      <link>/2009/02/should-we-call-it-mails-or-rurb-yahuda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/should-we-call-it-mails-or-rurb-yahuda.html</guid>
      <description>We just had a fun time at the latest LA Ruby Meetup, once again at UCLA. This time, we had presentations by James Foster from Gemstone, and Yehuda Katz from Engine Yard.
James Foster was showing MagLev, which is a Ruby VM based on top of the Gemstone Smalltalk VM. Not much to see here, just some Ruby code benchmarks running at about 4-5X faster than Ruby 1.8.6. That is, of course, not a very fair comparison, but no question that this is another Ruby VM to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Angeles &#43; Ruby = LARubyConf 2009</title>
      <link>/2009/01/los-angeles-ruby-larubyconf-2009.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 09:27:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/los-angeles-ruby-larubyconf-2009.html</guid>
      <description>It is with great excitement that I want to tell all of you about the first annual Los Angeles Ruby Conference. Thanks to the fine efforts of a bunch of LA&amp;rsquo;s hardworking Rubyists, and the generous financial support of AT&amp;amp;T Interactive, we are preparing to bring the noise to Los Angeles on April 4, 2009.
Too many of these wannabe cities have been smoking us with their regional conferences, but no more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In My Hood</title>
      <link>/2009/01/in-my-hood.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2009 09:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/in-my-hood.html</guid>
      <description>I was taking my morning constitutional with my youngest son, when I noticed my neighbor who programs at JPL had added a new placard to the artistic decor attached to his fence.
And who says there is no software development in Los Angeles?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April Is For AOL</title>
      <link>/2008/04/april-is-for-aol.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 08:38:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/04/april-is-for-aol.html</guid>
      <description>Last night was the always fun Los Angeles web application developer Meetup, this time at AOL in Beverly Hills. After navigating a veritable maze of cubes, we found ourselves in a fairly large screening room chock full of AV equipment, accompanied by a large pile of pizza boxes. A few moments later, the throng of LA-based developers shuffled in, ready for the latest and greatest. The prerequisites fulfilled, we got down to some serious techno-babble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Developer Fun In Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/2007/10/more-developer-fun-in-los-angeles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 08:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/10/more-developer-fun-in-los-angeles.html</guid>
      <description>Last night was the always entertaining Los Angeles Application Developer Meetup. L.A. is not known for the same massive quantity of developers as the bay area, for example, but having joined forces with the LA Ruby on Rails Meetup crew some time back, the monthly event is still growing.
This month&amp;rsquo;s was held at the impressive new digs of YellowPages.com, who have been busy building out a huge Ruby on Rails based local search replacement for their venerable 100K+ lines of Java code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun At Yahoo! In Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/2007/07/fun-at-yahoo-in-los-angeles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 22:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/07/fun-at-yahoo-in-los-angeles.html</guid>
      <description>Last Tuesday night was July&amp;rsquo;s Los Angeles Web Application Developer Meetup. This event is starting to get really good. Not only were there lots of people who came out, but our hosts Yahoo! actually bought us beer too. Hint to future hosts of the meetup&amp;hellip; be cool like Yahoo! and provide BOTH a projection screen and beer.
There were two especially fun presentations, at least to me. Jim Bumgardner of Yahoo showed off some of his really interesting web gadgetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Bit Of Merb In Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/2007/06/little-bit-of-merb-in-los-angeles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 13:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/06/little-bit-of-merb-in-los-angeles.html</guid>
      <description>Last night, I gave a short presentation on Ezra Z&amp;rsquo;s cool Ruby web development framework Merb at the Los Angeles Web Developer Meetup. Microsoft was kind enough to provide space at their new downtown offices, and even buy pizza. Can you say &amp;ldquo;(munch munch) Silver (crunch) light (munch) launch (gulp) budget&amp;rdquo;?
When I started my presentation, I asked the room how many people were using Ruby on Rails. Almost everyone in the place raised their hand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
