<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>be prepared on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/be-prepared/</link>
    <description>Recent content in be prepared on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 17:33:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/be-prepared/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Telecommuting as energy saver</title>
      <link>/2007/02/telecommuting-as-energy-saver.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 17:33:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/telecommuting-as-energy-saver.html</guid>
      <description>The Christian Science Monitor has an opinion piece called Telecommuting as energy saver which is nicely done.
Here are a few juicy excerpts:
 This new work freedom, properly handled, has the power to transform business, government, and home life. Telecommuters – those who work at home or on the road with no office at all – now number between 28 million and 32 million, according to some estimates&amp;hellip;
Cutting out that round-trip commute to the office – which averages about 23 miles – can save nearly $1,000 a year in gasoline and avoid putting more than 6,000 pounds of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What To Do When The Flu Comes For You</title>
      <link>/2007/01/what-to-do-when-flu-comes-for-you.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 18:22:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/01/what-to-do-when-flu-comes-for-you.html</guid>
      <description>My dear friend and former colleague Dan Rasmus has some really important points to make regarding IT operations and emergency preparedness in his blog entry Work Interrupted - Rapid Response in a Crisis.
Thank about how many warnings we have already had about potential pandemics. If it hits, it will be too late to make emergency plans&amp;hellip;we will need to be carrying out those plans, not talking about what they should be!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
