<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>space on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/space/</link>
    <description>Recent content in space on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2008 16:58:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Phoenix Has Landed</title>
      <link>/2008/05/phoenix-has-landed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2008 16:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/05/phoenix-has-landed.html</guid>
      <description>Earthlings, we have successfully landed another probe on the red planet. Congratulations to the team at JPL, University of Arizona, and everyone else who made this one happen!
Man, I just love space exploration&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drunk In Space</title>
      <link>/2007/07/drunk-in-space.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 14:31:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/07/drunk-in-space.html</guid>
      <description>Apparently, the altitude in orbit is not high enough for more than one of NASA&amp;rsquo;s finest. According to an independent panel, on at least two occasions astronauts were allowed to fly after flight surgeons or other astronauts warned that they were drunk, so drunk that they posed a flight safety risk.
You cannot have a machinist fabricating spacecraft parts who is unable to urinate in a little cup, but a DUI is space is not a problem that NASA is concerned with?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Without Air, No One Can Hear You Scream</title>
      <link>/2007/06/without-air-no-one-can-hear-you-scream.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 12:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/06/without-air-no-one-can-hear-you-scream.html</guid>
      <description>I was shocked to read about the ongoing problems with the life support computers onboard the International Space Station. Every time I hear of problems up there, I feel a serious rant coming on.
I grew up on science fiction books. In fact, I would have to say that the vast majority of my childhood was spent far away from this planet. Suffice to say, I am a serious supporter of space exploration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
