<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rubyconf on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/rubyconf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rubyconf on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 07:20:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/rubyconf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 Cool Things From RubyConf X</title>
      <link>/2010/11/10-cool-things-from-rubyconf-x.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 07:20:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/11/10-cool-things-from-rubyconf-x.html</guid>
      <description>This last week was the fantastic RubyConf X. It has been ten years of RubyConf and in celebration of this notable occasion, the organizers located it in New Orleans and opened up the registration to a lot more people then most years past. This had the clearly foreseeable consequence of turning the conference into a really fun time!
So here, in no particular order, are 10 cool things I saw or heard at the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying Robot: World Tour 2009 Continues</title>
      <link>/2009/11/flying-robot-world-tour-2009-continues.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 08:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/11/flying-robot-world-tour-2009-continues.html</guid>
      <description>As usual, no blog posts = a lot of other activity here at Flying Robot HQ. Among other personal stuff, my brother Damen Evans and I have been getting ready for the last public demos of @flyingrobot for 2009. And we are going out with style!
Later this week, we roll up to San Francisco to present at the prestigious RubyConf! Then, next week @flyingrobot and I will fly off to Madrid, Spain, to do our first European appearance at the awesome-looking Conferencia Rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2008 - Rubinius - Evan Phoenix</title>
      <link>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-rubinius-evan-phoenix.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 21:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/rubyconf-2008-rubinius-evan-phoenix.html</guid>
      <description>The Ruby VM wonkiness continued at RubyConf 2008 - Day 1. Next up we heard the &amp;ldquo;State of Rubinius&amp;rdquo; address on the status of the anointed heir to the Ruby federation. Evan Phoenix is a fun guy, and it proved to be a both informative and enjoyable session.
Evan says Rubinius is &amp;ldquo;meta-circular-ish&amp;rdquo;, and slow, but getting faster. They have a new VM that is written in C++, which is a sharp tool, and as such, it is possible to poke your eye out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going To RubyConf 2008</title>
      <link>/2008/09/going-to-rubyconf-2008.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 16:54:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/09/going-to-rubyconf-2008.html</guid>
      <description>Yes, it has been quite a while since I last posted. I have been busy with several interesting code things I will be talking about soon, along with my family&amp;rsquo;s annual trip to Spain (lots of good times, but no posting about that).
Busy, yes. but not TOO busy to make my plans to go to RubyConf 2008. November in Florida, I can just imagine it now&amp;hellip; hard core Ruby coding, jam sessions in the hotel, and maybe even some post-election riots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Werewolf vs. Vampyre</title>
      <link>/2007/11/werewolf-vs-vampyre.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 05:52:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/11/werewolf-vs-vampyre.html</guid>
      <description>I had read with mild amusement the minor dustup over the craze of Werewolf players at RubyConf 2007. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is, you can read about it here.
Some people just really enjoy playing social games. Let&amp;rsquo;s call them the Werewolves&amp;hellip; you know who you are, even if the rest of us do not.
Other people, however, view RubyConf as a place to get together with the other commiters on their beloved project, stay up all night, and crank out a new release before their presentation the next day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2007 - Day 3</title>
      <link>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2007 21:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-3.html</guid>
      <description>As day 3 of RubyConf 2007 began, the breakfast buffet had to remind us of its presence. This time, it was the main sound system that was taken out by the ultra-powerful toasters. When Dr. Nic was asked if he wanted to get started anyhow, he had to give two of his charmingly nasal &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; rhymes with &amp;ldquo;Pow&amp;rdquo; before MC David Black caught his meaning. This gave some of us a moment to try to catch up on the flurry of RubyConf blogging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2007 - Day 2 - &#34;The Ruby VM Smackdown Begins&#34;</title>
      <link>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-2-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 13:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-2-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</guid>
      <description>As the sun rose over the hills of North Carolina, the quiet betrayed a seething fire blazing in the hearts of three development teams. &amp;ldquo;Three teams enter, one team leaves!&amp;rdquo; Yes, I am talking about the main event, people, the one, the only, Ruby VM Smackdown! The room was jam packed, the anticipation was high.
As good fortune would have it, I was sitting right next to the head of the team who was my personal favorite to win the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2007 - Day 1 - &#34;Advanced Ruby Class Design&#34; - Jim Weirich</title>
      <link>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-1-advanced-ruby-class.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 10:57:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-1-advanced-ruby-class.html</guid>
      <description>Jim Weirich is a very smart guy. So smart that his presentation was not about complicated classes, but about Ruby itself and how to take advantage of it to simplify things. Jim&amp;rsquo;s background in computing is long and varied, something like a history lesson in programming languages. Here is the abbreviated list:
FORTRAN &amp;gt; C &amp;gt; Modula 2 &amp;gt; C++ &amp;gt; Eiffel &amp;gt; Java
and in parallel to this:
LISP &amp;gt; FORTH &amp;gt; TCL &amp;gt; Perl</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
