<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>futureruby on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/futureruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in futureruby on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 09:37:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/futureruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The FutureRuby Revolution Will Not Be On AOL - Part 2</title>
      <link>/2009/07/futureruby-revolution-will-not-be-on.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 09:37:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/07/futureruby-revolution-will-not-be-on.html</guid>
      <description>FutureRuby Day 2 began in a seemingly calm and reflective way. Coffees were sipped, and hangovers nursed. As the self-inflicted wounds from the Pravda-Vodka-Kalashnikov faded, Pete Forde, our leader and spiritual adviser, began a short sermon.
His message was simple: Vegas is a horrible place to hold RailsConf. And we should live in a manner that follows the &amp;ldquo;Four Agreements&amp;rdquo;. Seriously, yes, he said both of these things.
Pete told us of the source of his sudden enlightenment: Portland&amp;rsquo;s Jupiter Hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Have Seen The FutureRuby, And It Is Amazing - Part 1</title>
      <link>/2009/07/i-have-seen-futureruby-and-it-is.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 17:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/07/i-have-seen-futureruby-and-it-is.html</guid>
      <description>It was with tremendous excitement that my brother Damen and I had arrived in Toronto for FutureRuby. Not only were we getting to attend the reprise of what had been by all accounts the &amp;ldquo;Best. Conference. Ever.&amp;rdquo;, but we were going to be speaking about Project Flying Robot.
There had been many interesting interactions with various security personnel on the journey, thanks to the many small homemade electronic devices that make up our tiny squadron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready For Takeoff At FutureRuby</title>
      <link>/2009/07/getting-ready-for-takeoff-at-futureruby.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2009 09:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/07/getting-ready-for-takeoff-at-futureruby.html</guid>
      <description>I just realized it has been an entire month since my last post. Sorry! In case you were wondering, the always overambitious plans for Project Flying Robot have taken up more time than expected. And parts. Especially parts.
Lucky for us, the benefit of a hard deadline approaches: FutureRuby is coming up next week. My brother Damen Evans and I are going to be showing off our latest works in Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAV) based on Ruby Arduino Development (RAD).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
