<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>los angeles rubyconf on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/los-angeles-rubyconf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in los angeles rubyconf on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 11:40:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/los-angeles-rubyconf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Was A Guest Blogger At LARubyConf 2010</title>
      <link>/2010/02/i-was-guest-blogger-at-larubyconf-2010.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 11:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/02/i-was-guest-blogger-at-larubyconf-2010.html</guid>
      <description>Longtime readers of this blog know that I can really get into writing about Ruby conferences, and I had a great time this last weekend at LARubyConf 2010. This time, I got to try some thing new: I was guest blogging the conference for TheBitSource, which has been providing some great coverage of other tech events like PyCon and SCALE.
Please check out my complete recap from the 2nd annual Los Angeles Ruby Conference LARubyConf 2010 here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARubyConf 2009 - Jim Weirich - &#34;The Grand Unified Thoery of Software Development</title>
      <link>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-jim-weirich-grand.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 10:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-jim-weirich-grand.html</guid>
      <description>As the 2009 Los Angeles Ruby Conference (LARubyConf) drew to a close, our keynote speaker Jim Weirich took the podium. I have seen Jim speak several times, and he is both intelligent, as well as down to earth, which is a rare combination indeed.
The subject of his keynote would be anything but down to earth. In fact, it would have to be one of the most ambitious talks I have ever seen at a Ruby conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARubyConf 2009 - Blake Mizerany - &#34;Sinatra: the Ultimate Rack Citizen&#34;</title>
      <link>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-blake-mizerany-sinatra.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 12:19:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-blake-mizerany-sinatra.html</guid>
      <description>I was very happy when the next presenter at the Los Angeles Ruby Conference 2009 (LARubyConf) was Blake Mizerany, creator of the very cool Ruby micro-framework Sinatra. As long-time readers of this blog know, I am very into Sinatra.
There has been an incredible amount of work going into Sinatra lately, so I was very interested to catch up on what the team has been up to.
What is Sinatra? A Ruby Domain Specific Language (DSL) Mapping REST to simple actions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARubyConf 2009 - Danny Blitz - &#34;Herding Tigers: Software Development and the Art of War&#34;</title>
      <link>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-danny-blitz-herding.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 20:51:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-danny-blitz-herding.html</guid>
      <description>I had no idea what I was about to experience at Los Angeles Ruby Conference 2009 (LARubyConf) when Danny Blitz took the podium as the next presenter. I had seen him hanging out with his distinctive pompadour, tattoos, and leather jacket. He is a big guy, and hard to miss. But he had been pretty quiet till then, which was about to change radically.
Herding Cats is a term commonly used when describing the management of software teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARubyConf 2009 - Jeremy Evans - &#34;Sequel&#34;</title>
      <link>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-jeremy-evans-sequel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 20:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-jeremy-evans-sequel.html</guid>
      <description>The next session at the 2009 Los Angeles Ruby Conference (LARubyConf) was Jeremy Evans presenting Sequel, which is a very powerful database toolkit for Ruby.
Ruby originally had adapters for each database. The problem was that each was very database specific. This was a problem due to both SQL differences, as well as API differences.
no behavior
1997 - ruby-postgres was first created.
2000 - DBI
2004 - Active Record</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARubyConf 2009 - Aaron Patterson - &#34;Journey Thru A Pointy Forest, or You Suck At XML&#34;</title>
      <link>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-aaron-patterson-journey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 08:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-aaron-patterson-journey.html</guid>
      <description>The second presentation of the day at Los Angeles Ruby Conference 2009 (LARubyConf) was Aaron Patterson, XML maniac. I had a run at hardcore XML/XSL a few years back, and it has been a while since I walked the razor&amp;rsquo;s edge of the angle bracket. But Aaron is not just an aficionado, he is genuinely obsessed. Given that he is the maintainer of the Nokogiri and Mechanize gems, this makes me happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARubyConf 2009 - Dan Yoder - &#34;Resource Oriented Architectures and Why It Matters&#34;</title>
      <link>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-dan-yoder-resource.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 08:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-dan-yoder-resource.html</guid>
      <description>Lead-off man Dan Yoder started off the day&amp;rsquo;s proceedings at the Los Angeles Ruby Conference (LARubyConf) 2009, with a presentation on Ruby Waves called &amp;ldquo;Resource Oriented Architectures and Why It Matters&amp;rdquo;. Despite not getting the same attention that some Ruby frameworks have, the Waves team has been tirelessly working on it. According to Dan, the foundation of Waves has gotten pretty solid. Waves adds a lot of support for things over and above just handling http requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARubyConf 2009 Was A Big Success</title>
      <link>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-was-big-success.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 07:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/larubyconf-2009-was-big-success.html</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was the first ever Los Angeles Ruby Conference. Despite being located a bit out of the way, down in Tustin, the venue was actually completely amazing. Called the Marconi Automotive Museum, the place was like &amp;ldquo;Robin Master&amp;rsquo;s garage&amp;rdquo; quipped one attendee, being that it was FULL of Ferrari&amp;rsquo;s and other highly valuable and hot sports cars.
Thanks to the tireless efforts of Coby Randquist and JR Fent, along with a host of others, this first conference was a tremendous success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: Better To Burn Out Than Fade Away?</title>
      <link>/2009/03/project-flying-robot-better-to-burn-out.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 17:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/project-flying-robot-better-to-burn-out.html</guid>
      <description>We had made incredible strides forward in our construction of &amp;ldquo;Rogue 1&amp;rdquo; our autonomous blimp that we are building as the first implementation of flying_robot, our Arduino-framework for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles based on top of Ruby Arduino Development (RAD). We are also heavily influenced by the cool Blimpduino project. We were finally ready for a live test&amp;hellip; or so we thought. We inflated our envelope, and my brother attached the gondola that he has been carefully constructing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los Angeles &#43; Ruby = LARubyConf 2009</title>
      <link>/2009/01/los-angeles-ruby-larubyconf-2009.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 09:27:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/los-angeles-ruby-larubyconf-2009.html</guid>
      <description>It is with great excitement that I want to tell all of you about the first annual Los Angeles Ruby Conference. Thanks to the fine efforts of a bunch of LA&amp;rsquo;s hardworking Rubyists, and the generous financial support of AT&amp;amp;T Interactive, we are preparing to bring the noise to Los Angeles on April 4, 2009.
Too many of these wannabe cities have been smoking us with their regional conferences, but no more!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
