<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>railsconf on beer on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/railsconf-on-beer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in railsconf on beer on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 10:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/railsconf-on-beer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 - Day 2</title>
      <link>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-2.html</guid>
      <description>After the incredible energy of RailsConf Day 1, Day 2 seemed to slow down the pace a little bit. That was good for me, as I could spend some time catching up with friends both old and new, and not just attending sessions like an information junky. First would come the morning keynote speeches from Cyndi Mitchell of ThoughtWorks, and headliner Tim Bray of Sun Microsystems, with a short interlude from Charles Nutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 Is Sold Out</title>
      <link>/2007/02/railsconf-2007-is-sold-out.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2007 09:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/railsconf-2007-is-sold-out.html</guid>
      <description>My dear friends, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have your ticket for RailsConf 2007, you have missed the boat. All 1200 passes have now been sold out!
I suspect that most conferences have a short peak of sales right when the passes first go on sale, then sell the bulk of their registrations in the last few days before the start of the conference, if conferences are anything like concerts. Since most conference don&amp;rsquo;t have the draw of a big musical headliner, conferences sell discounted registrations for a short period of time, to encourage early registrations and guarantee that the conference sells the minimum number of attendees to break-even.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 Will Have Good Beer</title>
      <link>/2007/02/railsconf-2007-will-have-good-beer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 21:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/railsconf-2007-will-have-good-beer.html</guid>
      <description>Portland has good beer. There, now I&amp;rsquo;ve said it. One of the key benefits of holding the RailsConf 2007 conference in Portland has to be easily obtaining really good beer.
The McMenamins on Broadway is the closest place to the convention center to go where &amp;ldquo;Classics such as raspberry-tinged Ruby, medium-bodied Hammerhead and dark, strong Terminator Stout are always available.&amp;rdquo;
In between the fun of learning all about Rails 2.0, Capistrano 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
