<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>flying robot on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/flying-robot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in flying robot on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 08:15:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/flying-robot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flying Robot: World Tour 2009 Continues</title>
      <link>/2009/11/flying-robot-world-tour-2009-continues.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 08:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/11/flying-robot-world-tour-2009-continues.html</guid>
      <description>As usual, no blog posts = a lot of other activity here at Flying Robot HQ. Among other personal stuff, my brother Damen Evans and I have been getting ready for the last public demos of @flyingrobot for 2009. And we are going out with style!
Later this week, we roll up to San Francisco to present at the prestigious RubyConf! Then, next week @flyingrobot and I will fly off to Madrid, Spain, to do our first European appearance at the awesome-looking Conferencia Rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready For Takeoff At FutureRuby</title>
      <link>/2009/07/getting-ready-for-takeoff-at-futureruby.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2009 09:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/07/getting-ready-for-takeoff-at-futureruby.html</guid>
      <description>I just realized it has been an entire month since my last post. Sorry! In case you were wondering, the always overambitious plans for Project Flying Robot have taken up more time than expected. And parts. Especially parts.
Lucky for us, the benefit of a hard deadline approaches: FutureRuby is coming up next week. My brother Damen Evans and I are going to be showing off our latest works in Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAV) based on Ruby Arduino Development (RAD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: Supporting The Blimpduino</title>
      <link>/2009/05/project-flying-robot-supporting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 21:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/project-flying-robot-supporting.html</guid>
      <description>As Maker Faire approached, my brother Damen and I were very busy working on something cool: support for the now-shipping Blimpduino kit!
Thanks to the tireless efforts of Chris Anderson and Jordi Muñoz, the long awaited Blimpduino kit is now shipping at Makershed. As readers of this blog know, we have drawn a lot of inspiration from the Blimpduino. Now, we actually have 2 of them, and you can get your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: Getting RAD With The ATMega328</title>
      <link>/2009/04/project-flying-robot-getting-rad-with.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 15:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/project-flying-robot-getting-rad-with.html</guid>
      <description>I have been wanting to upgrade the hardware used in our Dorkboards for flying_robot, from the ATMega168, to the newer better faster ATMega328. More memory, and a faster UART for serial communications with the XBee modems in the same pinout = easy win. Thanks to a quick shipping turnaround from @adafruit I got them in before the weekend, so I could play a little bit today.
The first step was to upgrade my hard-working Arduino Diecimila to a 328.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: I Believe I Can Fly</title>
      <link>/2009/03/project-flying-robot-i-believe-i-can.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 13:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/project-flying-robot-i-believe-i-can.html</guid>
      <description>At long last, after many obstacles to be surmounted, yesterday we achieved liftoff. The blimp prototype &amp;ldquo;Rogue 1&amp;rdquo; of our flying_robot project to create a platform for Ruby Arduino Development powered Unmanned Aerial Vehicles has achieved an important milestone.
After our third complete rewiring of the main circuit board, two burned out Pololu micro serial motor controllers, some time reviewing the schematics of the Blimpduino project, and too many revisions to the basic software to list here, we had finally gotten everything ready for what would hopefully be a successful flight test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come Fly With Us At Los Angeles RubyConf 2009</title>
      <link>/2009/03/come-fly-with-us-at-los-angeles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 15:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/come-fly-with-us-at-los-angeles.html</guid>
      <description>Yes, the rumors are true, our talk for LARubyConf was accepted. If you want to see the first ever public live demonstration of flying_robot, the real thing, actually flying around and such, come check it out live and direct at the first Los Angeles Ruby Conference on April 4.
I do yet not know exactly what our demo will include, but from what we have been doing so far in the lab, you won&amp;rsquo;t want to miss this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: Better To Burn Out Than Fade Away?</title>
      <link>/2009/03/project-flying-robot-better-to-burn-out.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 17:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/project-flying-robot-better-to-burn-out.html</guid>
      <description>We had made incredible strides forward in our construction of &amp;ldquo;Rogue 1&amp;rdquo; our autonomous blimp that we are building as the first implementation of flying_robot, our Arduino-framework for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles based on top of Ruby Arduino Development (RAD). We are also heavily influenced by the cool Blimpduino project. We were finally ready for a live test&amp;hellip; or so we thought. We inflated our envelope, and my brother attached the gondola that he has been carefully constructing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: By Your Command</title>
      <link>/2009/03/project-flying-robot-by-your-command.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 13:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/project-flying-robot-by-your-command.html</guid>
      <description>Our flying_robot project for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles has been underway for a few weeks now. Much soldering, and playing around with cool Arduino tricks has been taking place. You can read more here, here, here, and here if you need to catch up.
One aspect that I have mentioned several times, but not gotten into much detail about, is our protocol for communicating with the UAV from the ground station. It is amazing to me, but there is still no dominant digital protocol for controlling UAV&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: The Flying Dorkboard</title>
      <link>/2009/02/project-flying-robot-flying-dorkboard.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 08:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/project-flying-robot-flying-dorkboard.html</guid>
      <description>As we proceeded along with our flying_robot project, one thing became abundantly clear: weight matters. The Arduino Diecimilla that we had been using up to this point, although a fine package for beginners, was just not going to make it when it came time to weigh in. Yes, there is the Arduino Nano, but it is not a cheap device. Also, it has a few options that were not important to us, like the integrated USB, since we planned on only using XBee based communication with the blimp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: A Compass, Two Motors, And A Servo</title>
      <link>/2009/02/project-flying-robot-compass-two-motors.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 11:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/project-flying-robot-compass-two-motors.html</guid>
      <description>Last weekend was a fantastic hardware/software jam session with my brother Damen, working on our autonomous Ruby Arduino Development (RAD) powered blimp. Lots of little pieces had been coming in the mail, my brother had been soldering, and I had been programming away. Both of us were eager to start putting it all together.
The first item of business was getting our bearings. We had acquired from Sparkfun a very cool HMC6352 digital compass module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: Getting All XBee With It</title>
      <link>/2009/02/project-flying-robot-getting-all-xbee.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 10:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/project-flying-robot-getting-all-xbee.html</guid>
      <description>We have been making some amazing progress on our flying_robot project. This post is actually from almost a week ago, but I have not had time to catch up blogging with what we have been getting accomplished.
As I had mentioned in my first posting, one of the reasons that we did not simply copy the Blimpduino, is that we do not want to use a standard R/C controller for manual control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Flying Robot: The Adventure Begins</title>
      <link>/2009/02/project-flying-robot-adventure-begins.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 08:22:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/project-flying-robot-adventure-begins.html</guid>
      <description>I love robots. OK, there, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone and gotten that out into the open. Like many programmers, I have long dreamed of dominating the world with my robot legions. Or failing that, at least getting my RoboSapien to walk around in a little circle by itself.
Recently, my brother Damen Evans and I decided that we needed to realize our ambitions, and began work on a flying robot. Yes, that is what I said.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
