<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jruby on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/jruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jruby on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 13:38:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/jruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2007 - Day 2 - &#34;The Ruby VM Smackdown Begins&#34;</title>
      <link>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-2-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 13:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/11/rubyconf-2007-day-2-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</guid>
      <description>As the sun rose over the hills of North Carolina, the quiet betrayed a seething fire blazing in the hearts of three development teams. &amp;ldquo;Three teams enter, one team leaves!&amp;rdquo; Yes, I am talking about the main event, people, the one, the only, Ruby VM Smackdown! The room was jam packed, the anticipation was high.
As good fortune would have it, I was sitting right next to the head of the team who was my personal favorite to win the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weighing In On The Upcoming Ruby VM Smackdown</title>
      <link>/2007/09/weighing-in-on-upcoming-ruby-vm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 10:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/09/weighing-in-on-upcoming-ruby-vm.html</guid>
      <description>Earlier today, I read with great interest the potentially inflammatory post where Ola Bini proclaims the Ruby VM wars already over, and basically divides the Ruby VM empire into two halves, with the center controlled by Rome, err, I mean Rubinius primitives.
I had already come to this conclusion a while ago. Not because I am smarter than anyone, FAR from it. Probably because I am more superficial, and easily impressed by meaningless characteristics, like how cool is the name Rubinius?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2007 =&gt; Ruby VM Smackdown</title>
      <link>/2007/09/rubyconf-2007-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 09:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/09/rubyconf-2007-ruby-vm-smackdown.html</guid>
      <description>I just registered for RubyConf 2007, which will be held Nov. 2-4 in Charlotte, NC. If you want a more intimate, more hard-core Rubyist experience, than what RailsConf is turning into, RubyConf looks to be it.
There not being that many tickets available, you better register right now if you want to go. I registered without even looking at the agenda first&amp;hellip; just filled out the registration form, and hoped it&amp;rsquo;s was not too late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby/Microsoft?</title>
      <link>/2007/05/rubymicrosoft.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/rubymicrosoft.html</guid>
      <description>Martin Fowler just posted on his bliki a little piece entitled RubyMicrosoft. As I read it, I felt a strange chill run down my spine. Perhaps a few words of explanation are needed&amp;hellip;
At RailsConf recently I stood at the Thoughtworks booth for a moment chatting up Fowler, and embarrassing myself by asking for a photo with him (he doesn&amp;rsquo;t pose for photos with people). Luckily, I was rescued by the arrival of Oli Bini, and an ensuing short discussion about JRuby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 - Day 2</title>
      <link>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-2.html</guid>
      <description>After the incredible energy of RailsConf Day 1, Day 2 seemed to slow down the pace a little bit. That was good for me, as I could spend some time catching up with friends both old and new, and not just attending sessions like an information junky. First would come the morning keynote speeches from Cyndi Mitchell of ThoughtWorks, and headliner Tim Bray of Sun Microsystems, with a short interlude from Charles Nutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ruby.NET Interview From Down Under</title>
      <link>/2007/03/rubynet-interview-from-down-under.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2007 15:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/rubynet-interview-from-down-under.html</guid>
      <description>An interview with Dr. Wayne Kelly has been put up on Channel 9, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s video interview site. Dr. Kelly is head of the Ruby.NET compiler project at the Queensland University of Technology in Australia. As always, I am eager to see progress on the .NET side of the Ruby language wars. I drank my coffee, and put on my phones for the 15 minute interview.
After watching the video, I must say I am a little underwhelmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JRuby Has Won The Rails Race vs. .NET</title>
      <link>/2007/03/jruby-has-won-rails-race-vs-net.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 21:34:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/jruby-has-won-rails-race-vs-net.html</guid>
      <description>So now it is official. The latest build from the JRuby team is now running Ruby on Rails in the JRuby runtime. Great work from that team! The Sunsters up top must be gloating right now.
And Microsoft is still MIA. Despite some hopeful signs of life, the silence is deafening from Ray Ozzie and the .NET camp (is that a band?). MS had better have some damn strong announcement at MIX vis-à-vis Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even eWeek Is Falling For Ruby</title>
      <link>/2007/02/even-eweek-is-falling-for-ruby.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 14:47:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/even-eweek-is-falling-for-ruby.html</guid>
      <description>Even that stanch old &amp;ldquo;enterprisey&amp;rdquo; publication eWeek has been giving some love to Ruby and Ruby on Rails. Today&amp;rsquo;s most recent article is entitled &amp;ldquo;Ruby, Ruby, When Will You Be Mine?&amp;quot;. Was this supposed to run on Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day? I&amp;rsquo;m definitely feeling the love in the title.
Anyhow, the author is all over the JRuby project. Messrs. Nutter et. al. have been building up the energy at the same time as the code base.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
