<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby on rails on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/ruby-on-rails/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruby on rails on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 23:05:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ruby-on-rails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gabba: A Ruby Gem For Doing Server Side Google Analytics Tracking</title>
      <link>/2010/11/gabba-ruby-gem-for-doing-server-side.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 23:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/11/gabba-ruby-gem-for-doing-server-side.html</guid>
      <description>Yo, Gabba! Gabba, hey? Gabba is a Ruby gem to do easy server-side Google Analytics tracking of page view and custom events. Gather around and I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how it works.
Google Analytics is the gold standard of website traffic reporting. In addition to tracking page views, one of the interesting capabilities it has is to track custom events. These could be shopping cart checkouts or video plays from clicking on a button in a Flash player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Hybrid Ruby on Rails Applications On EY-Cloud</title>
      <link>/2010/03/configuring-hybrid-ruby-on-rails.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 10:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/03/configuring-hybrid-ruby-on-rails.html</guid>
      <description>This last weekend, we completed migration of a slightly more complex Ruby on Rails application than the usual to Engine Yard&amp;rsquo;s EY-Cloud. It took a few tries, and a tiny bit of research, before we completely understood what to do to get it up and running with all of the needed capabilities. Naturally this was due to gaps in my own knowledge, and I wanted to post about what I had learned, and how awesome EY-Cloud really is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sparkline Some Interest With Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>/2010/01/sparkline-some-interest-with-ruby-on.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 12:12:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/01/sparkline-some-interest-with-ruby-on.html</guid>
      <description>Recently, I added some sparkline graphs to a Ruby on Rails application. A sparkline is a very small graphic that displays a large amount of information, typically shown over time, and usually embedded in some other text. Invented by the father of modern infographics Edward Tufte, the sparkline has become a fixture of many online applications that want to visually display some stats in a simple, integrated way.
When it come to adding sparklines into a Ruby on Rails application, there are a couple of different options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroku Has Launched</title>
      <link>/2009/04/heroku-has-launched.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 09:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/heroku-has-launched.html</guid>
      <description>Well, just a very short time after I started using Heroku, they went commercial. Yes, after their very successful beta period, where apparently 24,999 web sites other than mine were already hosting, Heroku is now offering a paid version of their service. I had a sneak peak at the pricing a few days ahead of time, but I was not able to talk. And despite my intentions of blogging this right away, the other demands on my time have kept me occupied till just now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroku, Why Haven&#39;t I Been Using You Till Now?</title>
      <link>/2009/04/heroku-why-havent-i-been-using-you-till.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 11:23:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/heroku-why-havent-i-been-using-you-till.html</guid>
      <description>Last night, I finally got around to deploying something on Heroku, an interesting service founded by my formerly LA-based Ruby programming chums Adam Wiggins, James Lindenbaum, and Orion Henry. I had played with their previous incarnation of the service, now known as &amp;ldquo;Heroku Garden&amp;rdquo; but only recently have I gotten to know a little bit more about the incredible offering they have evolved into.
Basically, the Heroku crew have addressed the question &amp;ldquo;how can I deploy my Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, or other Rack-based web application into a dynamic cloud of servers with ridiculous ease?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2009 Program Is Looking Juicy</title>
      <link>/2009/02/railsconf-2009-program-is-looking-juicy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 15:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/railsconf-2009-program-is-looking-juicy.html</guid>
      <description>I just noticed that there are already a whole bunch of the approved presentations for RailsConf 2009 on up the web site here.
It is looking really good already, go check it out. If you are into Ruby on Rails, you really should be going&amp;hellip; I am!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Long, And Thanks For All The SSH</title>
      <link>/2009/02/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-ssh.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 09:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-ssh.html</guid>
      <description>I read Jamis Buck&amp;rsquo;s posting late last night, about how he was retiring from involvement with Capistrano, Net:SSH and a few other closely related projects. First of all, the community owes him a lot for doing so much work on these crucial parts of the Ruby on Rails ecosystem.
Seems like he has fallen victim to his own project&amp;rsquo;s popularity. So many people using your code, and they start to expect things, and then demand them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should We Call It Mails, or Rurb? Yahuda Katz Clears Things Up At The LA Ruby Meetup</title>
      <link>/2009/02/should-we-call-it-mails-or-rurb-yahuda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/should-we-call-it-mails-or-rurb-yahuda.html</guid>
      <description>We just had a fun time at the latest LA Ruby Meetup, once again at UCLA. This time, we had presentations by James Foster from Gemstone, and Yehuda Katz from Engine Yard.
James Foster was showing MagLev, which is a Ruby VM based on top of the Gemstone Smalltalk VM. Not much to see here, just some Ruby code benchmarks running at about 4-5X faster than Ruby 1.8.6. That is, of course, not a very fair comparison, but no question that this is another Ruby VM to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Think I&#39;m Comatose</title>
      <link>/2008/11/i-think-im-comatose.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 10:50:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/i-think-im-comatose.html</guid>
      <description>This last weekend, I upgraded a pretty complex application to the latest Ruby on Rails, and consequently had to upgrade a bunch of the plugins. In the case of Comatose 2.0, this was well timed, as there is a new release.
If you have never heard of Comatose, it is a very cool mini-CMS that you add to your Rails app as a plugin. For cases where you have an applcation, and you want to put the &amp;lsquo;static&amp;rsquo; pages under the control of the users, while still integrating with your application, Comatose is the best option I have discovered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Like Cucumber</title>
      <link>/2008/10/cool-like-cucumber.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 16:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/10/cool-like-cucumber.html</guid>
      <description>Ever since I discovered Fitnesse a few years back, I have been increasingly obsessed with the idea of executable specifications and testable requirements. As far as I am concerned, Behavior Driven Development (BDD) is a very appealing way to get the &amp;ldquo;people who need the software&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;people who build the software&amp;rdquo; to understand each other.
For about 2 years, give or take, many Ruby on Rails developers have been switching to RSpec, or at least paying lip-service (giving rspec?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search Of Search</title>
      <link>/2008/05/in-search-of-search.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 15:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/05/in-search-of-search.html</guid>
      <description>My client was having troubles. The site was crashing, seemingly at random. QA was baffled, management concerned. After hunting thru logs, the culprit was found: the ferret search service.
Despite having configured acts_as_ferret to use the DRb server option, the &amp;ldquo;whole thing&amp;rdquo; would fall apart on a regular basis whenever the ferret daemon would crash&amp;hellip; which was pretty often. The ruby on rails plugin acts_as_ferret would revert to a local mode of operation, which would only make matters worse when competing mongrels would corrupt the index files on disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recaptcha On Rails</title>
      <link>/2008/02/recaptcha-on-rails.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 14:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/02/recaptcha-on-rails.html</guid>
      <description>UPDATED Oct. 15, 2009 with most current info
I hate implementing captchas. You know, those annoying things that your users think are deciphering hieroglyphics. I have hated them because I do not want to install a whole massive assemblage of software like ImageMagick/RMagick just to provide some basic protection from spam and bots.
To avoid this, I had hacked together a simple implementation using some free public captcha. However, a client recently turned on SSL on their signup page, and my free public captcha gave a nasty error cause of the domain name in the SSL certificate not matching the domain of their site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 Registration Is Open</title>
      <link>/2008/01/railsconf-2008-registration-is-open.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 11:13:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/railsconf-2008-registration-is-open.html</guid>
      <description>Get ready, get set, go!! The annual frenzy of registration for RailsConf 2008 has begun.
Yes, I have already received my registration confirmation. No, I have not received my speaker confirmation&amp;hellip;yet? Oh well, looks like RejectConf again!
See you all there&amp;hellip; ahem, not all of you, unless you register right now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Want My API</title>
      <link>/2008/01/i-want-my-api.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 22:47:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/i-want-my-api.html</guid>
      <description>I just ran into a really great resource for open source API documentation. Called gotAPI, it links in a delightfully searchable way all of the APIs we love, but turn out to not actually know. Well, we know them, just not well enough to have their numbers setup for speed dial on our cell phones. Or our code able to call them directly without looking up a reference first.
Here is a small sample of ones I will actually use regularly:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Grid With EC2</title>
      <link>/2008/01/on-grid-with-ec2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 10:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/on-grid-with-ec2.html</guid>
      <description>Lately, I have had a chance to get seriously into Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) service. I doubt any reader of this blog is unfamiliar with the existence of EC2, but many of you have probably not even gotten to the tire kicking stage, like I had been until recently.
Even after attending several sessions about Amazon&amp;rsquo;s EC2 at RailsConf 2007, I still had only a very general idea about the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And Here Comes The Money...</title>
      <link>/2008/01/and-here-comes-money.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2008 09:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/and-here-comes-money.html</guid>
      <description>I read with great excitement that Engine Yard, my favorite of the Ruby-centric hosting companies, was taking in a round of $3.5 million from Benchmark Capital. I am a big fan of Ezra, and the rest of the crew, and the whole waiting list thing for getting a new slice setup has been a big inhibitor of their growth.
Funny, however, the press coverage has called EY a &amp;ldquo;Ruby on Rails hosting company&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money In The Ghetto</title>
      <link>/2008/01/money-in-ghetto.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 10:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/money-in-ghetto.html</guid>
      <description>I keep thinking about Zed Shaw&amp;rsquo;s vitriolic (and newly updated) posting, and one particular aspect about it that seems to bother me. One way of looking at a ghetto is that is keeps people in. Another, is that is keeps outsiders away. In either case, it is an economy, like most any other. And like any economy, there are winners and losers.
What exactly is Zed complaining about? That the overall level of technical competence is very low, even among many self-proclaimed developers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zed Is Mad</title>
      <link>/2008/01/zed-is-mad.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 15:44:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/zed-is-mad.html</guid>
      <description>Zed Shaw has always been a rather curmudgeonly figure. I find him smart and hilarious, but of course many are rather insulted by his &amp;ldquo;tell it like he $%#@! well sees it&amp;rdquo; style. To me, Zed is like the Hunter S. Thompson of our community. The more your believe your own BS, the more he pisses you off.
Like Hunter S., Zed is a put up or shut up kind of person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sinatra, a Ruby web framework, and Why It Matters</title>
      <link>/2007/10/sinatra-ruby-web-framework-and-why-it.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 09:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/10/sinatra-ruby-web-framework-and-why-it.html</guid>
      <description>As followers of this blog know, I am very interested in the Ruby language itself, not just web development. But it is undeniable that Ruby has become popular largely due to web development powered by Ruby on Rails. However amazing Rails is, however, it is not the final web framework to be developed in Ruby.
When Ari Lerner first told me of the Sinatra project, I was interested to see where he was going with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Developer Fun In Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/2007/10/more-developer-fun-in-los-angeles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 08:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/10/more-developer-fun-in-los-angeles.html</guid>
      <description>Last night was the always entertaining Los Angeles Application Developer Meetup. L.A. is not known for the same massive quantity of developers as the bay area, for example, but having joined forces with the LA Ruby on Rails Meetup crew some time back, the monthly event is still growing.
This month&amp;rsquo;s was held at the impressive new digs of YellowPages.com, who have been busy building out a huge Ruby on Rails based local search replacement for their venerable 100K+ lines of Java code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun At Yahoo! In Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/2007/07/fun-at-yahoo-in-los-angeles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 22:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/07/fun-at-yahoo-in-los-angeles.html</guid>
      <description>Last Tuesday night was July&amp;rsquo;s Los Angeles Web Application Developer Meetup. This event is starting to get really good. Not only were there lots of people who came out, but our hosts Yahoo! actually bought us beer too. Hint to future hosts of the meetup&amp;hellip; be cool like Yahoo! and provide BOTH a projection screen and beer.
There were two especially fun presentations, at least to me. Jim Bumgardner of Yahoo showed off some of his really interesting web gadgetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CruiseControl.rb and RCov Are SO Good Together</title>
      <link>/2007/06/cruisecontrolrb-and-rcov-are-so-good.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/06/cruisecontrolrb-and-rcov-are-so-good.html</guid>
      <description>I spent a bit of time this morning getting CruiseControl.rb and RCov working together for a new client&amp;rsquo;s fairly LARGE Ruby on Rails (70+ models, 40+ controllers) project. If you are not familiar with CruiseControl.rb, it is the Ruby based continuous integration tool from ThoughtWorks. RCov, on the other hand, is a very well known code coverage tool for Ruby. The implementation was incredibly simple, but finding the information on how to get the two working together required a perusal of the CruiseControl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Bit Of Merb In Los Angeles</title>
      <link>/2007/06/little-bit-of-merb-in-los-angeles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 13:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/06/little-bit-of-merb-in-los-angeles.html</guid>
      <description>Last night, I gave a short presentation on Ezra Z&amp;rsquo;s cool Ruby web development framework Merb at the Los Angeles Web Developer Meetup. Microsoft was kind enough to provide space at their new downtown offices, and even buy pizza. Can you say &amp;ldquo;(munch munch) Silver (crunch) light (munch) launch (gulp) budget&amp;rdquo;?
When I started my presentation, I asked the room how many people were using Ruby on Rails. Almost everyone in the place raised their hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 - Day 2</title>
      <link>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-2.html</guid>
      <description>After the incredible energy of RailsConf Day 1, Day 2 seemed to slow down the pace a little bit. That was good for me, as I could spend some time catching up with friends both old and new, and not just attending sessions like an information junky. First would come the morning keynote speeches from Cyndi Mitchell of ThoughtWorks, and headliner Tim Bray of Sun Microsystems, with a short interlude from Charles Nutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 - Day 1</title>
      <link>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2007 18:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-1.html</guid>
      <description>I was primed and ready for RailsConf 2007 Day 1. The excitement was in the air, and the crowd was primed. We awaited a day absolutely packed with mind candy. Starting with Chad Fowler, David Heinemeier Hansson, Robert Martin, Adam Keys, Avi Bryant, and Ze Frank. Wow, what a lineup!
As Chad Fowler took the stage, his ukulele in hand, we eagerly awaited his opening remarks. Chad really did a great thing, by not just giving us the &amp;ldquo;feel-good rah-rah Rails is taking over the world&amp;rdquo; intro speech that most people probably expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 - Sessions (Day 0)</title>
      <link>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-sessions-day-0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2007 07:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-sessions-day-0.html</guid>
      <description>Well, I had just got back to my room after day 0 of RailsConf 2007, which was the tutorial sessions before the main conference began. After a fun evening of pizza and beer with the Pragmatic Programmers, I thought I would try to get down some thoughts about the day&amp;rsquo;s events.
Yesterday, I attended &amp;ldquo;Scaling Rails From The Ground Up&amp;rdquo; followed by &amp;ldquo;Harnessing Capistrano&amp;rdquo;. It is very hard to have tutorial sessions at a conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your attachment_fu Back Out Of The Database</title>
      <link>/2007/04/getting-your-attachmentfu-back-out-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2007 13:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/04/getting-your-attachmentfu-back-out-of.html</guid>
      <description>I have been busy the last few nights incorporating the brilliant Rails plugin called attachment_fu from Rick Olson aka technoweenie. If you do not know about attachment_fu, it is a complete solution to the problem of uploading image files attachments to include with your models.
First, I had to get past the initial hurdle of getting ImageScience and FreeImage correctly installed and working on my Mac. Despite the claims that Locomotive should have already had these in the bundle, I had to go thru a small process to get the prerequisites going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E Is For Editor Envy</title>
      <link>/2007/03/e-is-for-editor-envy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 16:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/e-is-for-editor-envy.html</guid>
      <description>I love it when I find out about a cool new tool. In this case, it is E, a Windows clone of the ubiquitous Mac text editor TextMate. Looks like this project has been around for awhile, but I just heard of it thanks to a blog entry about creating a Mac-like environment under Windows.
Installing E is not a small task, although it is not a difficult one. This is due to the fact that E relies heavily on Cygwin to support &amp;ldquo;bundles&amp;rdquo; which is how TextMate creates their oh-so-useful macro and template collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CruiseControl.rb: Continuous Integration Is About To Get Beautiful</title>
      <link>/2007/03/cruisecontrolrb-continuous-integration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 14:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/cruisecontrolrb-continuous-integration.html</guid>
      <description>At last, Ruby has a real Continuous Integration system, not just some crazy hacked-together solution. Nothing against crazy, hacked-together solutions, but your CI system is not the place for such madness. From those wonderful folks at Thoughtworks, we now have CruiseControl.rb, to join the CruiseControl and CruiseControl.NET offerings for Java and .NET projects respectively.
I have been a constant user of CruiseControl.NET for all of the MS-platform projects for the last couple of years, and having a powerful, flexible system has been great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aptana &#43; RadRails = Much Web Development Goodness?</title>
      <link>/2007/03/aptana-radrails-much-web-development.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/aptana-radrails-much-web-development.html</guid>
      <description>It was a couple of weeks ago when the RadRails team acknowledged that the ship had started to wander off course. Without any revenues, and with too few project contributors, the project was looking adrift. Could this be the end?
Do not fear, gentle reader. Last week, the announcement came at EclipseCon that the RadRails project is now part of the Aptana project. Up until this announcement, I had never heard of Aptana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JRuby Has Won The Rails Race vs. .NET</title>
      <link>/2007/03/jruby-has-won-rails-race-vs-net.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 21:34:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/jruby-has-won-rails-race-vs-net.html</guid>
      <description>So now it is official. The latest build from the JRuby team is now running Ruby on Rails in the JRuby runtime. Great work from that team! The Sunsters up top must be gloating right now.
And Microsoft is still MIA. Despite some hopeful signs of life, the silence is deafening from Ray Ozzie and the .NET camp (is that a band?). MS had better have some damn strong announcement at MIX vis-à-vis Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Computerworld Jumps In On The Rails Lovefest</title>
      <link>/2007/03/now-computerworld-jumps-in-on-rails.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 14:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/now-computerworld-jumps-in-on-rails.html</guid>
      <description>According to Computerworld today, Ruby on Rails is the number one of the &amp;ldquo;five most important technologies that you need to know about in 2007.&amp;rdquo; Oh yeah! As I wrote a couple of days ago, now even the oldest of the old school enterprise publications are showing the love for Ruby and for Rails.
That in itself is quite exciting. Another interesting point to note, is learned by looking over the list of the other four hot technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even eWeek Is Falling For Ruby</title>
      <link>/2007/02/even-eweek-is-falling-for-ruby.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 14:47:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/even-eweek-is-falling-for-ruby.html</guid>
      <description>Even that stanch old &amp;ldquo;enterprisey&amp;rdquo; publication eWeek has been giving some love to Ruby and Ruby on Rails. Today&amp;rsquo;s most recent article is entitled &amp;ldquo;Ruby, Ruby, When Will You Be Mine?&amp;quot;. Was this supposed to run on Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day? I&amp;rsquo;m definitely feeling the love in the title.
Anyhow, the author is all over the JRuby project. Messrs. Nutter et. al. have been building up the energy at the same time as the code base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gazing Into The ORM</title>
      <link>/2007/02/gazing-into-orm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2007 08:24:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/gazing-into-orm.html</guid>
      <description>Jeremy Miller has an interesting post today regarding Object Relation Mapping (ORM). Droves of developers are now flocking to ORMs via Ruby on Rails, Castle, or one of the other many projects in this space, so it is good to have people like Jeremy exploring from a real implementation perspective.
Anyhow, his post really is concerned with applications that use an existing database, have a large amount of logical processing. Simply applying an ORM without considering the logical implications of the data, not only fails to take advantage of the power of ORMs, but falls into a bit of a quagmire, with potentially a very non-DRY result.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
