<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mac on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mac on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 00:17:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My New MacBook Pro Rocks For Rails Development</title>
      <link>/2007/04/my-new-macbook-pro-rocks-for-rails.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 00:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/04/my-new-macbook-pro-rocks-for-rails.html</guid>
      <description>The last week or so I have been very busy playing with and setting up my new MacBook Pro. This is, in fact, my first post from it. After spending some time with it, I have to say that I am still extremely pleased! I have my Ruby on Rails environment all setup and working spendidly. I have my primary dev toolset CocoaMySQL, Locomotive, TextMate, and SVNx and now everything is pretty dialed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Say No To Vista?</title>
      <link>/2007/02/just-say-no-to-vista.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2007 09:49:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/just-say-no-to-vista.html</guid>
      <description>Security expert Bruce Schneier says not to use Windows Vista, due to the flaws of the Digital Rights Management (DRM) incorporated into the OS. No, really. One of, if not THE, top security expert says not to use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s newest OS.
To quote Mr. Schneier:
 Windows Vista includes an array of &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo; that you don&amp;rsquo;t want. These features will make your computer less reliable and less secure. They&amp;rsquo;ll make your computer less stable and run slower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching Back To The Mac Side Of The Force</title>
      <link>/2007/02/switching-back-to-mac-side-of-force.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2007 19:10:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/switching-back-to-mac-side-of-force.html</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time, I did really cool things at Apple Computer&amp;hellip;
It was during the reign of Jobs the First, and all was well with the world. Except for the installed base of Macs, and trying to sell businesses on buying Macs. Shareholder were incensed, board members impatient.
Even after the coup, and various poorly executed attempts to rectify the situation by the imposters Scully and Gassee could not change, and the kingdom was greatly endangered.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
