<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>railsconf 2008 on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/railsconf-2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in railsconf 2008 on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 21:14:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/railsconf-2008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 - Day 2</title>
      <link>/2008/06/railsconf-2008-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 21:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/06/railsconf-2008-day-2.html</guid>
      <description>Day 2 of RailsConf 2008 began with a keynote from Jeremy Kemper, uber-committer and now main man behind Ruby on Rails. According to the brief introduction by DHH, Jeremy did around one third of the Rails 1.0 release himself, cares deeply about the &amp;ldquo;whole thing&amp;rdquo;, and has been busy helping get RoR running on Ruby 1.9 and other platforms.
That must explain why Jeremy kept yawning incessantly during his presentation&amp;hellip; he is the reason DHH is able to get more sleep!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 - Day 1</title>
      <link>/2008/06/railsconf-2008-day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 13:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/06/railsconf-2008-day-1.html</guid>
      <description>As RailsConf 2008 - Day 1 began, there was no avoiding a sense of just how large the community was growing. With over 2000 attendees, the physical presence was bigger than ever. But, unlike the first two conferences, the growth of the community had triggered inexorable changes. Unbeknownst to most attendees at RailsConf 2008, a rebel alliance had formed itself. The caboo.se crew, longtime Ruby on Rails committers, had decided to stick it to the MAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Public: From Los Angeles To RailsConf 2008</title>
      <link>/2008/06/going-public-from-los-angeles-to.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 11:31:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/06/going-public-from-los-angeles-to.html</guid>
      <description>With the high cost (and carbon!) of transportation, as well as the burden of the increased time it takes to fight your way through the congestion, we all need to change the way that we navigate thru our daily lives. I had decided to take public transportation to get from my house in Los Angeles, to RailsConf 2008 in Portland, OR.
When I first mentioned my plans, several friends and family members were incredulous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 Better Be Good</title>
      <link>/2008/05/railsconf-2008-better-be-good.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 08:23:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/05/railsconf-2008-better-be-good.html</guid>
      <description>RailsConf 2008 is later this week, as if you all did not know that. Interestingly, this year it has not sold out like it did for 1.0 and 2.0. Increased capacity by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly? Or perhaps something else at work here&amp;hellip;
If you are not aware for the cost of transport, you have been living on another planet. Just the massive increase in time required to make the pilgrimage has been substantial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 Registration Is Open</title>
      <link>/2008/01/railsconf-2008-registration-is-open.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 11:13:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/railsconf-2008-registration-is-open.html</guid>
      <description>Get ready, get set, go!! The annual frenzy of registration for RailsConf 2008 has begun.
Yes, I have already received my registration confirmation. No, I have not received my speaker confirmation&amp;hellip;yet? Oh well, looks like RejectConf again!
See you all there&amp;hellip; ahem, not all of you, unless you register right now!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
