<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>railsconf on Dead Programmer SOciety</title>
    <link>/tags/railsconf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in railsconf on Dead Programmer SOciety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2009 15:17:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/railsconf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fear And Loathing At RailsConf 2009</title>
      <link>/2009/05/fear-and-loathing-at-railsconf-2009.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2009 15:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/fear-and-loathing-at-railsconf-2009.html</guid>
      <description>We were around Barstow on the edge of the desert, when the drugs began to take hold&amp;hellip; wait, that was someone else&amp;rsquo;s story. OK, restart.
We were around Barstow on the edge of the desert when the excitement began to take hold&amp;hellip; we were on our way to RailsConf 2009! No screaming bats, just loud pumping techno music to power the PT Cruiser. My designer, who was not old enough to be pouring beer on his chest, nor interested in facilitating the tanning process, said &amp;ldquo;What the hell are you yelling about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare For The RailsConf 2009 Jam Session</title>
      <link>/2009/02/prepare-for-railsconf-2009-jam-session.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 17:28:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/prepare-for-railsconf-2009-jam-session.html</guid>
      <description>I will be running the music BOF at RailsConf 2009 in Las Vegas. What does that mean? We&amp;rsquo;re gonna get down. All styles will be represented, so if you have an instrument or a voice, bring it.
We have a Google group started here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 - Day 2</title>
      <link>/2008/06/railsconf-2008-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 21:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/06/railsconf-2008-day-2.html</guid>
      <description>Day 2 of RailsConf 2008 began with a keynote from Jeremy Kemper, uber-committer and now main man behind Ruby on Rails. According to the brief introduction by DHH, Jeremy did around one third of the Rails 1.0 release himself, cares deeply about the &amp;ldquo;whole thing&amp;rdquo;, and has been busy helping get RoR running on Ruby 1.9 and other platforms.
That must explain why Jeremy kept yawning incessantly during his presentation&amp;hellip; he is the reason DHH is able to get more sleep!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 - Day 1</title>
      <link>/2008/06/railsconf-2008-day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 13:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/06/railsconf-2008-day-1.html</guid>
      <description>As RailsConf 2008 - Day 1 began, there was no avoiding a sense of just how large the community was growing. With over 2000 attendees, the physical presence was bigger than ever. But, unlike the first two conferences, the growth of the community had triggered inexorable changes. Unbeknownst to most attendees at RailsConf 2008, a rebel alliance had formed itself. The caboo.se crew, longtime Ruby on Rails committers, had decided to stick it to the MAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 Better Be Good</title>
      <link>/2008/05/railsconf-2008-better-be-good.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 08:23:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/05/railsconf-2008-better-be-good.html</guid>
      <description>RailsConf 2008 is later this week, as if you all did not know that. Interestingly, this year it has not sold out like it did for 1.0 and 2.0. Increased capacity by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly? Or perhaps something else at work here&amp;hellip;
If you are not aware for the cost of transport, you have been living on another planet. Just the massive increase in time required to make the pilgrimage has been substantial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2008 Registration Is Open</title>
      <link>/2008/01/railsconf-2008-registration-is-open.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 11:13:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/01/railsconf-2008-registration-is-open.html</guid>
      <description>Get ready, get set, go!! The annual frenzy of registration for RailsConf 2008 has begun.
Yes, I have already received my registration confirmation. No, I have not received my speaker confirmation&amp;hellip;yet? Oh well, looks like RejectConf again!
See you all there&amp;hellip; ahem, not all of you, unless you register right now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby/Microsoft?</title>
      <link>/2007/05/rubymicrosoft.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/rubymicrosoft.html</guid>
      <description>Martin Fowler just posted on his bliki a little piece entitled RubyMicrosoft. As I read it, I felt a strange chill run down my spine. Perhaps a few words of explanation are needed&amp;hellip;
At RailsConf recently I stood at the Thoughtworks booth for a moment chatting up Fowler, and embarrassing myself by asking for a photo with him (he doesn&amp;rsquo;t pose for photos with people). Luckily, I was rescued by the arrival of Oli Bini, and an ensuing short discussion about JRuby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 - Day 3</title>
      <link>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2007 07:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/railsconf-2007-day-3.html</guid>
      <description>By the time we got to RailsConf Day 3, only the most hard core remained. In other words, almost everyone. And we were glad to have stuck around, because some of the best content of the entire conference was yet to come. David Black, introduced two integral members of the Ruby on Rails team, Jamis Buck and Michael &amp;ldquo;Koz&amp;rdquo; Koziarski, the co-authors of the seminal &amp;ldquo;Rails Way&amp;rdquo; blog.
The Rails Way</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packing For RailsConf 2007</title>
      <link>/2007/05/packing-for-railsconf-2007.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2007 16:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/05/packing-for-railsconf-2007.html</guid>
      <description>I am packing my stuff for RailsConf 2007, and I am pretty excited. Last year&amp;rsquo;s conference was the best event I had been to in years! The growth in the momentum and enthusiasm in the Rails community has only accelerated in the last year, and I am giddy at the prospect of more fun brain candy!
I will be blogging from the conference, but not moment to moment like some quicker multitaskers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 Is Sold Out</title>
      <link>/2007/02/railsconf-2007-is-sold-out.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2007 09:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/railsconf-2007-is-sold-out.html</guid>
      <description>My dear friends, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have your ticket for RailsConf 2007, you have missed the boat. All 1200 passes have now been sold out!
I suspect that most conferences have a short peak of sales right when the passes first go on sale, then sell the bulk of their registrations in the last few days before the start of the conference, if conferences are anything like concerts. Since most conference don&amp;rsquo;t have the draw of a big musical headliner, conferences sell discounted registrations for a short period of time, to encourage early registrations and guarantee that the conference sells the minimum number of attendees to break-even.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RailsConf 2007 Will Have Good Beer</title>
      <link>/2007/02/railsconf-2007-will-have-good-beer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 21:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/railsconf-2007-will-have-good-beer.html</guid>
      <description>Portland has good beer. There, now I&amp;rsquo;ve said it. One of the key benefits of holding the RailsConf 2007 conference in Portland has to be easily obtaining really good beer.
The McMenamins on Broadway is the closest place to the convention center to go where &amp;ldquo;Classics such as raspberry-tinged Ruby, medium-bodied Hammerhead and dark, strong Terminator Stout are always available.&amp;rdquo;
In between the fun of learning all about Rails 2.0, Capistrano 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Will Be At RailsConf 2007</title>
      <link>/2007/02/i-will-be-at-railsconf-2007.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 14:36:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/02/i-will-be-at-railsconf-2007.html</guid>
      <description>I just checked my email, and saw that registration has just opened for RailsConf 2007. I went to last year&amp;rsquo;s conference, and it was the most interesting and exciting event in the software industry I had been to in years!
If you are interested in going, I suggest that you register immediately. Last year&amp;rsquo;s event sold out in a couple days. When they added 100 additional spots last year, those sold out in hours!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
